Today we are going to make a polymer clay bowl.
In this next step we are going to create the canes to decorate our polymer bowl.
So what we are going to do, we are going to take two contrasting colors.
I am going to use black and white.
There is nothing more contrasting than that.
And we are going to roll our black, soften it up and then we are going to roll our white, soften it up.
We are going to roll our white piece and then we are going to do the same thing to our black piece.
So basically we are going to get two flat pieces of contrasting color and it doesn’t have to be perfectly shaped.
And you are going to place one on top of the other and then you are going to try to remove any edges.
You are going to mold them down or pull some out but you are going to try to make it so that it’s even.
What we are making is a flower shaped cane and in order to do that we need to have a nice flower center and it looks really pretty if the center is a swirl.
So now what we are going to do, we are going to maybe take a rolling pin, do an extra little roll, we are going to roll this lengthwise.
You want to make sure you have that first on in pretty tight.
Then you can bring it in a little and roll it but you don’t want to press too hard.
You want to make sure that its a nice even log but you don’t want to smush it too much, or stretch it too much because we are trying to keep that swirl shape that we made.